Hank Chen

User Experience Designer

Enthusiastic and self-driven User Experience Designer. My love of design does not only stops at front end digital design. My background in architecture and industrial design has taught me the beauty of spatial design and physical product design. I thrive on simplicity as I believe less is more when it comes to design.

CONTACT

480-840-5065 hankchen9299@gmail.com www.hankchen.us Fairfax, VA

SKILLS

User Experience Design User Interface Design User Research

User Experience Testing Product Design

Prototyping User Flows Responsive Wireframing

Visual Mockups 3D modeling

TOOLS & SOFTWARES

HTML5 & CSS3 JavaScript

jQuery

Adobe Creative Suites

Invision Draw.io Balsamiq

Dreamweaver
Axure RP 8
Google Forms
Google Analytics

EDUCATION

Virginia Tech Aug 2010 - May 2016 B. Architecture 2016 Minor Industrial Design

PROJECTS

Tape Measure

Web App Design

Self-initiated design project of a platform that improves daily tasks of the construction trade.

Analyzed research data and surveys of needs and experience gathered through former colleagues in the industry.

Designed the branding and logo through Illustrator and created the wireframes and prototype with Axure RP 8.

BlocShop Ecommerce Website

Created wireframes and designed interfaces, logo, branding for an ecommerce platform after observing a potential market for student artists and individual artists.

Conducted research on targeted user (colleagues from school) for needs and desired features.

Developed the prototype of landing, browsing and product pages using HTML5, CSS3 and jQuery from scratch.

Paycrave Mobile App Design

Designed the wireframes and interfaces of an Android mobile application as an alternative of Yelp specialized on food trucks with additional feature such as ordering and payments.

EXPERIENCE

Bloc.io, Web Design Apprenticeship

Oct 2016 - Jul 2017

Developed rounded UIUX skills through a 36 week course with the mentorship of the co-founder of Made by Munsters.

Produced wireframes with Photoshop and prototypes with Invision for user testing.

Developed basic front-end interfaces with HTML5, CSS3, Java Script and jQuery.

Teel Construction, Assistant Superintendent

Jul 2016 - May 2017

Collaborated with Superintendent for the completion of projects. Supervised construction crew of 20 people and delivered a \$500,000 project on time as an assistant which in turn saved the company \$5,000 in staffing cost.

Proposed strategies to compete against large corporation in the acquisition of student talents resulted in decreased staffing cost, increased flexibility for senior superintendents and advertised the name of the company.

isARK Studio. Architectural Intern

May 2015 - July 2016

Bridged communication between 6 subcontractors and supervisor.

Aided the design process from schematic design and design development to the production of construction drawings of 4 projects.